y'all heard me talk about the benefits
of massages before but you know going to
see a massage therapist can be really
expensive over time not everybody has
the budget to spend on a massage gun so
a really popular alternative is busting
out the good old trusty foam roller to
work out any knots that you may be
dealing with living fit sent me over
their foam roller so today I'm going to
spend some time breaking it down for
y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
I've got a foam roller from livingfit
I'm gonna be breaking down for y'all
from the price some features some pros
and cons and of course who should or
maybe should not buy one of these now
before I get started with all of that I
gotta let you know we've reviewed a lot
of foam rollers on barbin.com so if you
want to browse our top picks just go
ahead and search bar Bend best foam
rollers and you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
best
[Music]
okay so let's talk about what I like
about this foam roller well first of all
it's pretty big as you can see and
that's you know going to be beneficial
you have a pretty large surface area
right here for you to work with and
that's going to be really nice as you go
to lay down on it similar to most foam
rollers right it's pretty lightweight
which is going to be really helpful if
you go to throw it in your car you're
traveling or you know definitely even
just when you're cleaning it and it's
also pretty firm you know it's not too
firm to where it hurts but it's firm
enough to you know get those knots out
and the material that it's made from is
going to prevent it from losing its form
and obviously you know that is a very
good thing
foreign
[Music]
now what about those potential cons you
may run into with this foam roller well
let's talk about the size I know I just
got done saying that it was a positive
thing about how big it is but you know
in terms of traveling this really isn't
going to be the you know best for that
because of how long it is and you know
some foam rollers also fold in on
themselves so that's going to make it
easier to throw into a backpack duffel
bag suitcase whatever it may be that's
something that you can't really do with
this specific foam roller other than
that though it's pretty much just gonna
be personal preference you know other
than the size some people may want a
foam roller that's more firm maybe less
firm than this one and the texture
pattern is also going to be big for a
lot of people so some people like a foam
roller that's pretty smooth some of them
like the texture to be you know more
abrasive I guess you could say have
deeper ridges you know it might help you
you know work out those knots a little
bit better but really other than the
size and traveling it's really just
going to boil down to personal
preference which is definitely the case
with all foam rollers
[Music]
okay so you can purchase yourself a
living fit foam roller for right around
25 bucks which that's not you know the
most expensive in the world it's
actually a pretty good deal now you can
definitely find some foam rollers for
like 10 bucks or something but there's
also some for around 60 bucks now I
don't necessarily think that 60 foam
roller is going to be you know Leaps and
Bounds better than what this is and you
know provide more benefits but as I
mentioned just a second ago you know
some of those options are going to be
able to fold in on themselves and you
know that added portability is most
likely driving that price that added
feature you know at the end of the day
though 25 bucks for this foam roller you
know it's a pretty good deal you know
it's going to last you a long time as I
mentioned you know the material it's
made from it's going to allow it to keep
its form for a really long time and it's
also firm enough to you know work out
those you know Troublesome knots that
you may be dealing with
[Music]
all right so let's quickly break down
the build and you know some of the
features you're going to find with this
foam roller so I mentioned the material
and how it's you know not going to lose
its form over time well that's because
it's made from ethylene vinyl acetate
what is that basically it's a safe
alternative from PVC you know it's not
too firm to where it's going to hurt to
lay down on so you know it's a little
bit comfortable I guess a little soft
but you know it's not going to lose its
form as I mentioned because of that
material it's 36 inches long it's got a
six inch diameter you know plenty of
surface area for you to work out those
knots as I mentioned it's also available
in black and blue so a couple different
buying options here but as you can see
it's really lightweight I'm just kind of
tossing it around it's going to be
helpful you know especially when you're
cleaning it you definitely want to do
that and it also has a nice textured
pattern right here you have a whole lot
of hexagons all over the place and you
know that pattern is what is going to be
able to work out knots
all right so let's go ahead and do a
quick walk around with this foam roller
as you can see you know you got your
living fit branding right here if you
didn't already know that now you know I
really like the pattern right here you
know you got a bunch of hexagons all
over the place that's really you know
going to be effective as you go to work
out those knots this thing is 36 inches
long it's got a six inch diameter it's a
pretty you know big surface area for you
to work with and as you can see it's
pretty lightweight you know I can kind
of toss it around do whatever I don't
know how much it weighs but honestly it
can't be more than a pound it's really
really lightweight now once again it's
available in blue and black you know you
get a couple different buying options
there and
if you don't know how to use one well
you're in luck because I'm going to show
you exactly how to do so so basically
you know just set it on the ground I'm
dealing with some back tightness right
now so
just go ahead and line your body up
wherever you know you're experiencing
that tightness and just simply roll
that's why it's called a foam roller
just simply roll back and forth for you
know really however long you want to not
too long but you know more than five
seconds obviously and you're gonna be
able to work out those knots now let's
say you need to use it on your
hamstrings you know you just had a leg
day and you're hurting well just simply
set it on your hamstrings and do the
same thing you can do one leg like this
at a time or you could do both legs if
you really wanted to really it doesn't
matter and you know there's a lot of
other ways you can do this as well so
definitely keep that in mind these are
pretty versatile
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the people who
might want to purchase this foam roller
well if you are in fact looking for a
Dependable foam roller it's not going to
break down on you lose its form only
after a couple of months I think this is
a really good option for you to consider
specifically because of the material
that it's made from and you know I would
imagine most if you want an effective
foam roller right well this is a really
good option without having to spend 60
bucks or so and because it's big you
know you have a big surface area to work
with as I mentioned for you to work out
those Kinks
foreign
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this foam roller it's a
whole lot of personal preference that's
really going to drive that so you know
because of the size as I mentioned it's
not going to be the best to take on a
trip with you unless you're driving so
you know if you're wanting something to
throw into your suitcase whatever it may
be you're definitely going to want one
that's a lot smaller than this right
here other than that I mean it's all
going to come down to the texture you
know the pattern on it some people may
want a vibrating foam roller because you
know gonna have an increased chance most
likely of loosening up those stiff
muscles so other than the size it's
really just personal preference and how
the actual foam roller is constructed
that's about all I have for you guys
today on the living fit foam roller I
like using this thing before my workouts
you know to help me warm up but it's
also really helping me out lately with
this knot I've had my back for a really
long time because of the size you know
you're going to be able to hit a lot of
your muscles but because of that size it
might not be the best that for anybody
who's looking to travel with theirs
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was helpful and I was able to
tell you what to expect with this foam
roller as always stay posted for my next
video but for now head over to
barbin.com you can read more about this
product just search bar Bend livingfit
foam roller review our article is going
to pull up for you and you can read all
the details everything we talked about
here today I'll see y'all next time
thank you